### **Dmitry Smirnov** (BSc, MSc, PhD candidate)

E: dmi.smirnov07@gmail.com | P: +358503015072 | 02260, Espoo, Finland, Iivisniemenkuja 4 B 17

**Skype**: dikabraz | **LinkedIN**: fi.linkedin.com/in/dmismirnov

Personal Pages: http://becs.aalto.fi/~smirnod1 (includes links to Git)

Languages: Russian (native), English (fluent), Finnish (conversational), German (basic)

## **Data Science & Analytics**

Proactive, solution-focused data analyst with background in cognitive neuroscience, meets deadlines and has an immense drive to see projects through to completion. Adaptive and efficient at working together with multidisciplinary crews. Possesses practical knowledge in "big data" mining, predictive modeling, statistical inference, programming and machine learning. Thrives when a problem requires fast understanding, agile data mining process and quick delivery. Likes to learn new tools and technologies, and, what is most important for him, get things done and working.

**Core competencies include:** predictive modeling, time series analysis, (Bayesian) statistics, exploratory data analysis and data visualization, programming (Python, R, Matlab, bash), machine learning, project management, neuroscience, fMRI data acquisition and analysis, scientific research methodology.

**Also knows:** SQL, parallel computation, MapReduce, Stan and PyMC3 (probabilistic programming), working knowledge of command line Unix (bash, worked with Linux for past 5 years), psychology.

## **Professional Experience**

Aalto University, School of Science, Department of Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering, Brain and Mind Laboratory, January 2011 – Present

Internationally acclaimed laboratory, performing cutting-edge neuroscientific research.

### PhD Candidate

Managed research projects through the full cycle of development, including planning, data collection, analysis and scientific article writing and publication. Developed analytic software for laboratory usage. Taught master level biomedical statistics and experimental methods courses for Aalto University students.

- Successfully accomplished multiple projects studying human brain functioning in complex naturalistic environment using fMRI, exploratory data analysis, machine learning and predictive modeling techniques.
- Significantly reduced time costs for running data preprocessing and analyzes on terabytes of neural data by developing utilities and pipelines in Matlab, R and Python and parallelizing them on available cluster computing resources. Used Git version control system. Complete toolbox is used in multiple laboratories.
- Taught Experimental and Statistical Methods in Biomedical Research using R programming language. Supervised student experimental projects and provided tutoring.
- Presented scientific results in talks and posters on multiple international conferences.

### Innova Systems, December 2009 – November 2010

Major online entertainment provider in Russia, CIS, Europe and Brazil, which has been on the market for over 7 years and has published multiple successful MMORPGs.

## **Customer support manager (GM)**

Supported player community in technical and gaming problems, administrated live customer support system, managed events, participated in strategic development of project and its support structure.

- Increased rate and efficiency of support department response by 80% by optimization of support system, integrating it with user community and creating process guidelines for effective communication between working groups.
- Decreased rate of user problem reports by creating guidelines for solving most common issues.
- Decreased connectivity issues experienced by players by conducting a research of common causes of network problems and preparing solutions together with network engineering group.

## Lomonosov Moscow State University, Laboratory of Work Psychology, November 2007 – May 2009

*Top-rated institution for higher education.* 

### Research assistant

Supported laboratory in technical aspects, provided scientific research assistance, presented laboratory achievements at exhibitions and conferences.

- Analyzed eye-tracking data for RFBR (Russian Foundation for Basic Research) project №08-06-00284a: "Microstructure of cognitive actions in consecutive and recursive performance of computerized tasks".
- Provided support in performing eye-tracking and psychological experiments.
- Presented technologies developed in laboratory at public events.

### **Education**

# Lomonosov Moscow State University, Industrial Psychology Department, 2004 – 2009 BSc, MSc in Psychology.

Master's thesis: Dynamics of human functional states while solving different computer-based tasks.

### **Traits**

Fast learner, able to work with limited or no supervision, assertive, open for challenges, able to manage lots of balls in the air, able to identify and troubleshoot critical issues, strategic thinker, confident when dealing with complexity, ambiguity and uncertainty, persuasive, tactful, able to motivate and lead, proficient at intuitive explanations of complicated concepts.

**Personality:** outdoorsy and social person – likes rock climbing in Salmisaari gym and Turku area, cycle touring with sub24 Helsinki crew, and frying marshmallows on the bonfire. Musical – half-way finished Moscow conservatory (piano), plays guitar and ukulele, and sings (performed in BECS department band). Dreams of making his own cooking show and has the most tactile cat in the world.